A Guide to theJoe Maynard Papers 1960-1989
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Joe Maynard Papers 1960-1989
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
10884
This collection consists of ca. 85 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Access to the collection shall only be granted by specific permission of the depositor.
Acquisition Information
This material was loaned to the Library by Joe Maynard of Charlottesville, Virginia, on November 6, 1989
Scope and Content Information
This collection is comprised of ca. 85 items, 1960-1989, pertaining to William S. Burroughs A Bibliography 1953-73, compiled by Joe Maynard and Barry Miles, and to Burroughs. There are a setting copy, master sets of galley proofs and page proofs, and a paste-up of the book. There is also a set of first galley proofs (electrostatic copy) for Cities in the Red Night by Burroughs. Other material includes letters from William S. Burroughs (1914- ), Lawrence Ferlinghetti (1920- ), Brion Gysin (1916-1986), Barry Miles, and others; photographs of Burroughs, Joe Maynard, Allen Ginsberg, and Brion Gysin; and printed and other memorabilia concerning Burroughs.
Letters, 1973-1986, from William S. Burroughs discuss work on the bibliography. On June 10, 1973, he has received a copy of Maynard's bibliography and informs him that Barry Miles has recently completed an exhaustive bibliography and offers to arrange for him to receive a copy. Maynard and Miles collaborated on the bibliography, keeping Burroughs apprised of developments. On August 1, 1975 [photocopy only], Burroughs reveals that he is now in a position to write the preface since receiving the abstract of the bibliography from Maynard and the nearly completed copy of Miles' work. He also asks him to let Miles know directly of his preference to have the book published by the University Press of Virginia. There are also copies of three letters, January 23, 1976, December 10, 1977, and April 18, 1978, to Walker Cowen, University Press of Virginia, supporting the exhaustive and scholarly bibliography of Burroughs' works by Maynard and Miles, sending 50 copies of the signature sheet, signed and numbered by Burroughs, and complimenting Cowen and his assistant on their contributions. His letter of August 4, 1986 [photocopy only], discusses the news of his friend Brion Gysin's death on July 13 in Paris, France. There are also several Christmas cards from Burroughs.
Letters, 1972-1987, from various persons in the literary field are chiefly concerned with gathering material for the bibliography and subsequent revisions. There is information about the printings of certain books by Burroughs from Fred Jordan of Grove Press (October 26 and November 20, 1972), Lawrence Ferlinghetti of City Lights Publishing House (February 14, August 8 and 21, 1974), and "Michael" (December 19, 1978). On July 22, 1976 [photocopy only], Brion Gysin turns down a request for a cover design as he is not feeling up to it, and sends best wishes for the project and greetings to Miles. Allen Ginsberg's introduction is mentioned by Richard Elovich (August 12, 1976) and Richard Aaron of Am Here Books (September 6, 1976). Letters from Barry Miles mention a visit with Richard Aaron and his sister, Julia, and the Burroughs limited edition scrapbooks and "Letters to Ginsberg" (April 9, 1980); seeing Victor Bockris and Burroughs in New York and collecting Burroughs' works (September 11, 1981); and, the third draft of the Ginsberg manuscript (August 27, 1987).
There are several photographs of William S. Burroughs, most autographed and some inscribed. Other photographs depict Joe Maynard alone and with Allen Ginsberg, and Brion Gysin. The printed material includes a program and poster for The Nova Convention (1978), with an autograph of John Giorno (1937- ), art exhibit catalogs of Burroughs' work (1988), various descriptions of Burroughs' literary works, and two buttons.
Contents List
- Manuscripts
  - Cities in the Red Night by William S. Burroughs, first galley proofs (electrostatic copy) 1980 (Box 1)
  - TMs William S. Burroughs A Bibliography 1953-73, with typed revisions and autograph notations 1977 (Box 1)
  - TMs William S. Burroughs A Bibliography 1953-73, setting copy 1977, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - William S. Burroughs A Bibliography 1953-73, master set of galley proofs with autograph revisions and instructions to the printer 1977 (Box 1)
  - William S. Burroughs A Bibliography 1953-73, master set of page proofs with autograph revisions and instructions to the printer 1977 (Box 1)
  - TMsS Fragment of a Short Story by William S. Burroughs, inscribed For Joe Maynard/all the best/ William Burroughs,n.d., 2 leaves (Box 2)
  - William S. Burroughs A Bibliography 1953-73 1977 (Box 2)
- Correspondence
  - Letters from William S. Burroughs to Joe Maynard 1972-1989, 26 items (Box 2)
  - Letters to Joe Maynard 1972-1987, 22 items (Box 2)
- Topical
  - Photographs 1978, n.d., 13 items (Box 2)
  - Printed Material re Exhibits and Lectures of William S. Burroughs 1960-1988, 16 items (Box 2)